walsworthyearbooks.com 2016-07-08

# Privacy Policy » School Yearbooks | Walsworth

### Walsworth Privacy Policy

**Walsworth is committed to your privacy.**

Privacy is a primary concern to us at Walsworth. Protecting the privacy of our customers is important to Walsworth and our employees. We want you to understand what information we collect, and how we use it.

Walsworth is committed to safeguarding your privacy on its websites located at [www.walsworthyearbooks.com](http://www.walsworthyearbooks.com/), [www.yearbookhelp.com](http://login.walsworthyearbooks.com/login/help/login.html) and [www.yearbookforever.com](https://yearbookforever.com/#). This Privacy Policy does not apply to products or services provided, or information obtained, other than through these websites. Please read the following policy to understand how your information will be treated. This policy may change from time to time, so please check back periodically.

If there is an important change in our collection, use, or disclosure practices, we will attempt to send you a notice via email if you have provided us with an email address. Please keep in mind that some of the services mentioned specifically in this policy may not be available on the site at this time. If you have questions concerning this policy, please contact Privacy Officer. This Privacy Policy is effective as of August 12, 2009.

To review our privacy policies for young children, see the section below titled Special Privacy Provisions for Children Under 13. We comply with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA). We strongly encourage parents to participate in their children’s online activities and monitor their children’s use of networking services, information posting, and engagement in other electronic communication. For more information about COPPA or children’s privacy, please visit [www.ftc.gov/news-events/media-resources/protecting-consumer-privacy/kids-privacy-coppa](https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/media-resources/protecting-consumer-privacy/kids-privacy-coppa).

Walsworth Yearbooks is also an official signatory of the Student Privacy Pledge, a new effort to protect the privacy of student information organized by the Future of Privacy Forum (FPF) and the Software & Information Industry Association (SIIA). The Pledge now has commitments from a leading group of K-12 school service providers. The commitments are intended to detail ongoing industry privacy practices that meet and go beyond all federal requirements and to encourage service providers to more clearly articulate these practices to further ensure confidence in how they handle student data. For more information about the Student Privacy Pledge, please visit [studentprivacypledge.org/](http://studentprivacypledge.org/).

The purpose of our policy is to inform you about the types of information we gather about you online when you visit our site, how we may use that information, whether we disclose it to anyone, and the choices you have regarding our use of and your ability to correct the information.

**What information does Walsworth collect from me?**

Walsworth collects information in several ways depending on the website:

**Walsworthyearbooks.com and Yearbookhelp.com:** When you enter the Members Only portal on the walsworthyearbooks.com website, we will collect the login information (user name and password) provided by the yearbook adviser. We may also collect personal information such as your name and staff position in connection with yearbook projects.

**Yearbookforever.com:** When you purchase products, including yearbooks, on yearbookforever.com you are asked for certain ordering information. This includes type and quantity of items purchased, the student’s first and last name, the student’s grade, the payee’s first and last name (if different from the student), address of the buyer including city, state and zip code, phone number of the buyer, email address (optional, but required for order confirmation), shipping street address (including city, state and ZIP), bill to address, payment method, credit card type, account number, expiration date, three-digit security code and cardholder name.

**All Walsworth Sites:** We may ask you for information at other times, such as when you report a problem with our site or services, or contact the company via the corporate email address. If you contact Walsworth, we may keep a record of that correspondence.

If you contact us by email, we use your email address (which is personally identifiable information) only to respond to your specific request or question. If we ask for a parent’s email address, we keep that information and use it only for the purpose of providing notices to parents, administrating account permissions and parental approvals, product purchasing, requesting parental consent as required under COPPA, and keeping a record of such consent and approvals.

If you believe that any inaccurate or inappropriate information has been obtained or disseminated through your use of our websites, you should contact Walsworth.

**How does Walsworth use cookies and other technology?**

We may collect information through technology to make our site more interesting and useful to you. For instance, we collect IP addresses and use technology to track traffic patterns on the sites. Once you have logged into a site, we may track your activities by using logs of database transactions and server interactions. This data is used to improve your online experience. We also use this information to understand which areas of our websites are most appealing or least appealing. Our sites also use cookies, which are pieces of information that a website sends to your computer while you are viewing the website. Cookies provide information to the site so that the site will remember who you are. These technical methods may involve the transmission of information either directly to us or to another party we authorize to collect information on our behalf.

**How does Walsworth use the information?**

Walsworth’s primary goal in collecting information is to improve the sites and provide the user with the best possible experience on the sites.

Except as provided herein, only Walsworth will have access to individuals’ account information. We also may do research on our users’ demographics and behavior based on the information provided to us upon registration, gathered from transaction activity, from our server log files or from surveys. This research may be compiled, analyzed or sold on an aggregated basis, which does not include information identifying individual users. Walsworth also may share this data with business partners or other third parties.

Walsworth may also share certain information with third parties such as affiliated educational institutions, but such sharing is on an opt-in basis only. (See Choice/Opt-In section below).

**Who is collecting information?**

When you are on a Walsworth site and are asked for personal information, you are sharing that information with Walsworth and its affiliates. If personal data is to be collected and/or maintained by any company other than Walsworth, we will attempt to notify you on the website or in an updated version of this Privacy Policy. If you do not want your data to be shared, you can choose not to allow the transfer by not using that particular service.

Please be aware that other websites to which we link may collect personally identifiable information about you when you visit those sites. The information practices of other websites linked to our websites are not covered by this Privacy Policy.

**With whom does Walsworth share my information?**

We will not disclose any of your personally identifiable information except when we have your permission or under special circumstances, such as when we believe in good faith that the law requires it or under the circumstances described below. The following describes some of the ways that your information may be disclosed.

Content: Information posted to the Members Only section of the walsworthyearbooks.com site will be shared with other participants in your school yearbook project.

Transaction Information: We will disclose your payment, billing and shipping information to third-party payment processing companies in order to complete your transaction.

Blinded Data: We may disclose “blinded” aggregated data and user statistics to prospective partners and other third parties, and for other lawful purposes. Blinded data is data that does not identify an individual person.

Students: All information shared by you online will be made available to your parent or guardian and you expressly consent to Walsworth’s disclosure of such information to your parent or guardian.

Parents: All information shared by you online may be made available to your students, school representatives and school administrators and you expressly consent to Walsworth’s disclosure of such information to your students, school representatives and school administrators.

Schools: All information shared by you online may be made available to your school administrators and you expressly consent to Walsworth’s disclosure of such information to your school administrators.

Other: We also may disclose your information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating Walsworth’s Terms of Use Agreement, or may otherwise be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) Walsworth’s rights or property, other Walsworth website users or customers, or anyone else that may be harmed by such activities. We may disclose or access account information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it and for administrative and other purposes that we deem necessary to maintain, service and improve our products and services.

We occasionally hire other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, including packaging, delivering, answering customer questions about products or services, sending postal mail, providing investor information, and processing data. We will only provide those companies the information they need to deliver the service, and they are contractually prohibited from using that information for any other purpose.

As we continue to develop our business, we may buy or sell businesses or assets. In such transactions, confidential customer information generally is one of the transferred business assets. In the event of a transaction involving the sale of some or all of Walsworth’s businesses, customer and site visitor information may be one of the transferred assets. In such case, the transferred information may become subject to a different privacy policy.

**How can I control my personal information?**

Walsworth offers its users choices for the collection, use and sharing of personal information. You may login at the applicable Walsworth site if you wish to view, edit or delete your personal information from our database, and we will use commercially reasonable efforts to accommodate your request.

**How does Walsworth protect financial-related information?**

Keeping your personal financial information private is vitally important to us. As a matter of policy and business practice, Walsworth does not sell personal information provided by its customers. At Walsworth, we conform to the Payment Card Industry (PCI) Data Security Standard for the protection of financial credit card information. This standard provides security requirements for credit card merchants to safely receive, secure, transport and store your sensitive personal and financial data. We may report a security breach to you as required by law. Any user statistics that we may provide to prospective partners regarding financial matters are provided in the aggregate only and do not include any personally identifiable information about any individual user. We will transfer your credit card number or other personal information to the appropriate credit card company, bank or payment processing company in order to process any online payments.

**What security precautions are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of my information?**

Your Walsworth Account Information and Walsworth Profile are password-protected so you have access to this personal information. We use secure socket layer (“ssl”) encryption technology for all transmission of credit card numbers, bank account numbers, passwords, and registration information, and in other areas of the website where the SSL padlock appears. Remember to sign out of your Walsworth account and close your browser window when you have finished your work. This is to ensure that others cannot access your account by using your computer when you are away from it.

Because of the global nature of the Internet, when you give us information, that information may be sent electronically to servers outside of the country where you originally entered the information. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Except as discussed above or otherwise designated, the sites do not use security encryption measures over the Internet. Therefore, information that you disclose by use of our sites, by posting a message or using email, potentially could be collected and used by others since email and message postings are not encrypted. This may result in unsolicited messages from third parties or use of such information by third parties for their own purposes, legal or illegal. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, Walsworth cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or from our services, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we use commercially reasonable efforts to ensure its security on our systems.

**Choice/Opt-In**

Except for administrative messages needed to run the sites and administer your account, our website provides users the opportunity to opt-in to receiving communications from us. Where indicated, just click on the appropriate radio button when completing a survey, form, or registration process to opt-in to the designated communication. For example, you may be able to opt-in to communications with Walsworth’s strategic partners and participate in research products and communications with other third parties. By default, you are excluded from communications with affiliated educational programs unless you opt-in. We operate in this manner to protect your choice as a consumer of our services. Please allow a reasonable period of time for your changes to take effect.

To ensure that you will not receive recurring marketing information from us unless you choose to, we will provide simple instructions on every marketing email from Walsworth for you to let us know that you have chosen to stop receiving such emails from us.

**What else should I know about my privacy?**

Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose information online, that information is accessible to other customers and users. Ultimately, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and/or any account information. Please be careful and responsible whenever you are online.

When you or we end your customer relationship with us, we will treat the information we have about you as if you were still our customer.

**Special Privacy Provisions for Children Under 13**

We carefully follow the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA). COPPA requires us to inform parents and legal guardians about how we collect, use, and disclose personal information that we receive from children under 13 years of age. We must obtain the consent of parents and guardians in order for children under 13 years of age to use certain website features.

**How does Walsworth notify parents if our Privacy Policy changes?**

We may amend our Privacy Policy at any time, including portions applicable to Young Children. We will provide Parents notice by email of any material changes in the way we intend to collect, use, and/or share personal information of young children. Parents should continually update their personal information to provide us current email addresses. We will apply material changes in our Young Children Privacy Policy only in conformance with applicable law, including any applicable provisions of COPPA that require parental consent.

**Who do users contact with questions or concerns about our Privacy Policy?**

If you need further assistance, please [send an email](mailto:marketingyearbooks@walsworth.com) with your questions or comments or write us at:

Walsworth  
7300 West 110th Street, Suite 600  
Overland Park, KS, 66210  
Attn: Privacy Policy

You may also telephone us at 800-369-2965, ext. 5769. If you are not 18 years of age or older, you must have your parent or guardian’s permission to call this number.
